Martin Nolan

Mobile: 07734203854

Email: martinnolan_1@live.co.uk GitHub: https://github.com/mnolan99

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/martinnolan0110

"An innovative, ambitious and highly capable first-class Computing Science and Mobile Web Development graduate with a strong academic background and a passion for technology and business."

I have delivered various software engineering projects and have gained valuable professional experience as a result of working within financial services over the last 5 years. Throughout this time, I have established expert analytical and problem-solving skills, a fine eye for detail and I am very confident in my ability to identify inefficiencies and deliver solutions in an effective and efficient way.

Technologies Used

- HTML5/HTML
- React

GitHub

CSS

Java

PHP

SQL

- JavaScript
- Python
- Web3/Blockchain

jQuery

Django

Education

SEPTEMBER 2021 - AUGUST 2022

MSc Mobile Web Development (First - Expected) / University of the West of Scotland

As part of my dissertation project, I have designed and developed a Web3 blockchain marketplace application that employs Web3 technologies to allow users to purchase items using test cryptocurrency on the Polygon network. The application was built using React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Solidity. This was an independent project which further developed my proficiency in web development whilst enriching my critical thinking, research skills, and project management.

In addition, I developed a variety of front-end CRUD web applications using HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, and SQL that allow users to connect to a local database to create, read, update, and delete entries in the database. This project received a grade of over 90% and enhanced my front-end development skills.

SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2021

BSc Computing Science (First) / University of Glasgow

I have designed, developed, and deployed an interactive health and fitness application for Amazon's Alexa. This application allows users to complete a variety of workouts, meditation, and guided breathing sessions. I independently managed this project through the end-to-end product life cycle, from initial requirement gathering to certification and deployment on the Amazon Skill Store. This project improved my time-management and project management skills, whilst allowing me to employ industry-standard software practices and tools in a disciplined and organised manner.

Furthermore, I have designed, analysed, and deployed a large python-based web application which. This application made use of different APIs to allow users to view, compare and rate restaurants in their local area. The project enhanced my skills of developing applications within a distributed environment by using a variety of web technologies, protocols, and development tools.

Employment

OCT 2017 - PRESENT

Customer Service Adviser / Santander UK, Glasgow

- Taking ownership and problem solving to respond to customer queries in an efficient and timely manner by providing information on banking policies, products, and services
- Led a team of new members of staff to ensure that they were fully trained on all processes and were comfortable dealing with customer queries
- Part of a small team helping to detect trends in colleague knowledge gaps or procedural failures, introducing new ideas to improve these areas by meeting regularly with senior managements
- Empathising with customers who have fallen victim to scams or fraudulent transactions, whilst employing standards set out by the FCA
- Handling queries relating to fraudulent payments that have been identified by the UK-wide Adeptra Fraud detection system
- Additional responsibilities include 3rd party card dispute handing, security breach detection, and quality checking

This role has allowed me to develop my numerical and computer skills further and I have learned to prioritise work, be flexible and adapt to change in a challenging and highly regulated environment.

NOV 2016 - APR 2017

Sales Associate / Currys PC World, Livingston

- Building a rapport with customers daily, dealing with various enquires including complaint handling
- Working as a team in a fast-paced environment to drive sales and exceed a very high standard of targets in a high-pressure environment

This role exposed me to face to face customer handling. I learned to handle customer complaints and stay focused and succeed in a pressurised and target driven environment. I was also rewarded colleague of the month by achieving the highest sales figure.

JUN 2015 - JUN 2015

Work Placement / Skyscanner, Edinburgh

- Website debugging sessions with various teams throughout the business
- Live system testing with software developers using Microsoft Access
- Meetings with company stakeholders & CEO to discuss business goals for the upcoming year

Volunteering & Activities

- Raised over £7000 for the Anthony Nolan Trust by coordinating numerous fundraisers including a charity race night, sponsored walk and a sponsored skydive
- Participated in 'Sleep in the Park' which helped to raise awareness and money for homeless people across
 Scotland